acklandsgrainger.com 2015-03-19

# Acklands-Grainger : Industrial Supply, Safety Equipment and Fasteners

? 

**Customer Privacy Policy**

Acklands-Grainger Inc., its subsidiaries, parent company, affiliates, successors and assigns (collectively "AGI" and "we") are committed to protecting and safeguarding your personal information. We use information we collect about you to facilitate the provision of our online services and to provide you with a more personalized experience. We have created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to protecting your privacy.

This Privacy Policy sets out AGI’s privacy practices and policies and is intended to comply with the federal government's privacy legislation, the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ and applicable provincial privacy laws. **By using AGI’s products and services, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy.**

**Personal Information**

Personal Information is information that identifies you as an individual. It includes information such as your name, address, telephone number, birth date, social insurance number, e-mail address and financial information. We may gather personal information from your credit application, your purchase of goods or services (including through your method of payment), a contest or sweepstakes registration, your visit to our website(s) and your suggestions and feedback. We may also request personal information from time to time in order to enable you to participate in and enjoy various AGI product and service offerings.

**Personal Information Collection and Use by AGI**

**We collect information from you directly**. For example, we collect information from you when you register on the site, participate in a survey, or fill out a form requesting information from us.

**We collect information from you passively**. We (or vendors acting on our behalf) use common collection techniques like cookies, and web beacons. This policy describes how and when we use these practices.

**We obtain information about you from third parties with whom we work**. We may collect information about you from our suppliers, resellers, and other business partners.

We collect and use your personal information and information on your use of our products and services and our web sites (together, the " ** _Information_** ") only: (i) to establish and maintain responsible commercial relations with customers and to provide ongoing services and offers; (ii) to understand customer needs; (iii) to develop, enhance, market or provide products and services; (iv) to manage and develop our business and operations, including customer fulfillment, billing and collection efforts as well as personnel and employment matters; and (v) to comply with any legal and regulatory requirements, including requirements or requests of government agencies or pursuant to a subpoena or other legal proceeding.

AGI's web servers collect general data pertaining to each web site visitor, including but not limited to, the IP address, tracking codes, the domain name, the web page, the length of time spent and the pages accessed while visiting www.acklandsgrainger.com. This may also include GPS locations for some of our mobile applications. We also collect personal information and transactional information provided by companies and web site visitors that purchase products from www.acklandsgrainger.com. This information includes contact information, shipping information, credit cardholder name, and card number/expiration date. We may also retain the content of the communications that are sent to our customer service representatives.

If you choose not to provide the requested Information, or choose to disable the cookies on your browser as explained below, AGI may not be able to offer you some of the personalized products and services that depend on this type of information to function. You may also not have full functionality of the AGI web sites, or review them fully. 

We may request you to provide additional Information for security purposes such as identifying you when you call us with respect to your account and services. You do not have to provide it to us, but if you do, it will help us to ensure that we take instructions with respect to your account only from you. If you decide not to provide such information to us, that may limit our ability to take your account instructions from you. If possible we will try to arrange an alternative way to provide service to you.

**What are “cookies” and how do we use them?**

You should also be aware that information and data may be automatically collected through the standard operation of our Internet servers or through the use of "cookies".  “Cookies" are small text files that contain a unique identification number that is transferred from a web site to the hard drive of your computer so that we may: (a) recognize repeat users; (b) track usage behavior; and (c) compile aggregate data that will permit content improvements and targeted advertising. Our cookies do not extract information from your hard disk. You should be aware that we cannot control or prevent the use of cookies or any information obtained through such cookies by advertisers or third party content providers. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, most browsers permit you to disable the cookie feature. However, you are advised that doing so may limit your use of certain features on the AGI web sites.

**Personal Information Disclosure by AGI**

Your Information, including personal information, may be shared with Acklands-Grainger Inc.'s subsidiaries and parent company, and for customer administration and technological back-up purposes. For such purposes, personal information relating to you may be transmitted outside of Ontario or Canada. Personal information is subject to the laws of the country where it is stored, and as AGI may be storing and processing personal information in the United States, the use and disclosure of your personal information may be subject to the _USA Patriot Act_.  If you have any concerns in this regard, please contact our Privacy Officer as set out below. ****

**Who has Access to your Information?**

Occasionally, we, or any of our suppliers or partners, may host a contest or promotion where it will be your option to enter and your option to provide the requested information. Data collected during a promotion or contest is typically shared with the sponsor or co-sponsor. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to participate in the promotion or contest.

AGI may disclose, on a confidential basis, to any third party with whom we have business relations, certain relevant information relating to your dealings with us and our products and services. AGI does not sell your Information. AGI may enter into third party agreements from time to time for the purposes of providing you with products and services we think may interest you and may share your Information with these third parties solely for these purposes.

We may share Information with potential business partners of, or investors in, AGI. We may provide Information, including customer information, as security for an investment in AGI. We may provide Information, including customer information, to third parties who purchase assets from AGI where such information is relevant to the assets so sold. In this regard, Information may also be disclosed when required or permitted to do so by law or legal process, or in connection with a sale, transfer or reorganization of our business, in which case we will require that any personal information will continue to be treated in accordance with this policy. Any such disclosure to third parties is made/will be made under a confidentiality agreement with the third party who is required not to disclose or use the Information for any other purpose other than is necessary to fulfill the agreement with AGI.

Please note that AGI’s web sites may contain links to other sites and may occasionally allow other sites to be co-branded with AGI. We cannot represent or guarantee that other sites’ privacy policies conform to our own and we cannot be responsible for any actions of such third parties. When accessing or reviewing sites linked from AGI’s web sites remember that such sites may have privacy policies that differ from those of AGI. AGI’s privacy policy does not cover third party data collection and AGI does not assume any responsibility for the actions of any third parties. You should make every effort to read the individual privacy policies of the partners, advertisers or co-sponsors before accessing any such web site or providing any personal information to any such web site.

We reserve the right to conduct statistical analyses of your behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of AGI’s products and services, AGI’s proposed products and services, the AGI web sites and the Internet and to provide suppliers with Information such as the number of purchasers of their products or services. We will provide only aggregated data from these analyses to third parties. Also, you are advised that we may permit third parties to offer subscription and/or registration-based services through the AGI web sites. We are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties and you should check the applicable privacy policy of each such third party before providing any personal information to a third party web site.

**Online Behavioral Advertising**

We may share information with a marketing partner who is working with us to provide you with a program or service, such as serving advertisements that are tailored to your interests. These ads may be served on our websites and other third party sites that you visit. The content of these ads may be determined based on information gathered as you browse our website. It may also be based on information collected during your transactions with us. The companies we work with participate in the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. This program provides users with the ability to opt-out of receiving online behavioral advertising by visiting [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). If you delete your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

**What security measures do we have in place to protect your Information?**

AGI has security measures in place to attempt to protect your Information against loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. We will keep your Information in secure data storage in order to safeguard it from unauthorized access. Only authorized employees or contractors have access to the Information you provide. While AGI cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we make reasonable efforts to prevent such occurrences. We will keep your Information for as long as it remains necessary or relevant for the identified purposes or as required by law.

You are responsible for the security of any passwords provided to you. Do not divulge your ID and/or password to anyone.

You should also be aware that when personal information is voluntarily disclosed in the public areas of the AGI web sites and the Internet, that information, along with any information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from third parties. Such activities are beyond our control. AGI cannot ensure and/or warrant the security of any Information transmitted online. You are advised that conveying personal information online is done at your own risk and you remain solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of passwords and/or any account and/or credit information.

**Consent**

By submitting personal information to AGI, you acknowledge and agree that you have consented to the collection, use and disclosure practices set out in this Privacy Policy as they relate to your personal information. You further consent to our collection from, verification with and communication to any third party for the above purposes. You also authorize these third parties to give us personal information relating to you. You agree that we may disclose Information to: (i) any person who, in our reasonable judgment, is seeking the Information as your agent or (ii) a person involved directly or indirectly in supplying the product or service to you, including, without limitation, our sales and marketing agents, our transportation companies, our invoices printing and mailing suppliers, our data processors and our suppliers to the extent the Information is required and used only for purposes such as the efficient supply of products and services to you, and provided that such person is required to keep the Information confidential; or (iii) a person retained by us to collect amounts which you owe us or to enforce our rights under our terms and conditions, if the Information is required for, and is to be used only for that purpose and that person is required to keep such Information confidential.

We may also use Information in our records for as long as it is needed for the purposes described above and your consent remains valid after the termination of our relationship with you to the extent those purposes continue.

You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting AGI's privacy officer as set out below. Withdrawing your consent may limit your ability to use our services and access our web content. AGI may not be able to offer you some of the personalized products and services that depend on this type of information to function. You may also not have the full functionality of the AGI web sites, or the ability to review them fully.

**What is our Opt-out Policy?**

You may request to decline receiving promotional and/or marketing information from us. Notwithstanding your wish to cease receiving such promotional and/or marketing information, we reserve the right to contact you regarding account status, changes to any AGI service agreement and other matters relevant to the underlying service and/or the personal information collected.

You may not opt out of product notifications, billing notifications, account renewal or other emergency announcements. ****

If you wish to opt-out of receiving online behavioral advertising, you can do so by visiting  [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). The companies we work with participate in the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising, and this program provides users with the ability to opt-out of receiving online behavioral advertising by visiting that website. If you delete your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice. ****

**Can you Access, Edit or Delete your Information?**

At your written request, we will: (a) provide you with reasonable access to your Information that is in our records within a reasonable time period; and (b) use reasonable efforts to allow you to update or correct information which you state is incorrect to the extent such updating or correction will not compromise our privacy or security interests. In the event that we are unable to grant you access to your Information, we will provide you with a written explanation of the reasons for denying access. Please contact our Privacy Officer, whose contact information is set out below, to make such a request.

**Questions concerning Privacy Issues and Access to your Information**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy, you may contact us through our web site or call us at the numbers provided on our web site or on your invoice.

If you have any unresolved issues concerning the protection and handling of your personal information, or if you wish to make a request to access, edit or delete your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer at the following address:

Privacy Officer  
Acklands-Grainger Inc.  
90 West Beaver Creek Road  
Richmond Hill, Ontario L4B 1E7  
Tel.: 1(800) 668-8989 ext. 5246  
Fax: (905) 709-3544  
E-mail: [privacyofficer@agi.ca](mailto:privacyofficer@agi.ca)

June 2012
